There is a brother there, you have a new woman.
You love your woman - a very kind woman -
but mistakenly, you found yourself getting married to somebody outside
and you have rented a secret place - a bedroom flat somewhere.
You have now begun to manage your time - sometimes you sleep here, another time, there.
We are just telling you - this coming year, you cannot continue it.
It will be very dangerous for you.
Come out for your deliverance.
The brother I am talking about, please come out.
In confirmation of the prophecy, a man comes out of the congregation
and walks towards Prophet T.B. Joshua.
Are you not too young?
Yes, Man of God.
I am confused.
You are confused?
Yes, Man of God.
But this one is never confused!
Prophecy Time
If you are confused, this one will never be confused.
He said, I am confused.
If you are confused, can that place be confused?
I can't hear you.
[No!]
It is him that is confused but that place is a different place.
Next year, what you are doing secretly now - if you try it next year, you will die.
Because the woman you put in that place, they are tracing you and they will get you.
Very early in the morning, they will just find that they have killed you somewhere.
So, by the time you go to the other one, you will know you are confused.
He is a young man. You are very handsome; please don't let this world deceive you.
Okay? So, I want to see you.
Thank you, Man of God.
What has your real wife done to you?
Nothing, Man of God.
I will invite her.
How old are you?
Thirty-six years.
Okay, wait for me.
The other one, I will invite her.
We will pray with her and point her to her future success
and I will say, 'Please, leave my brother'.
All we are saying, leave my brother.
Prophecy Time
The woman is not confused; this man is confused.
So, the one who is not confused should be able to tell the one who is,
"Please, go back to where you are coming from".
STANDARD FOR LIFE
The SCOAN Sunday Service
These are the issues you will never ask the man of God to pray for you.
You will leave the important issue - you would be telling the man of God a different thing.
This is why we are here. Anything that could be dangerous for you,
you want Jesus to bring it and separate you from them.
I said he should bring the wife at home
and the wife at home is maybe hearing this for the first time.
My name is Mr Emmanuel.
I am from Togo.
The woman beside me is my wife, which I'm wedded with.
During the prophetic service on Saturday, the man of God prophesied
that there was a young man here who was married
but had secretly rented a house for another woman outside.
Immediately I heard it, I found it difficult to come out.
I waiting to see if someone else would come out.
Suddenly, it felt like there was a vibrating machine inside me.
My body could not be controlled any longer; everything was vibrating seriously.
Did you listen to that?
He said that when I was saying it, he was looking for someone to come out.
But before he finished looking round the church -
he looked at this side of the church but before he looked back,
something hit his heart.
You know Jesus loves you.
He has a way of taking you.
I mean, He is your Creator.
He said he could not breathe again.
He had to quickly come out.
I looked around but didn't see anyone else coming out.
At the time my body started vibrating, I started hearing, "Pack your things and run".
I don't know how I got to the front of the altar.
Everything the man of God said is completely true - one hundred percent true.
A woman was introduced to me by a friend who supplied sand to us.
She already had six children.
I was helping them.
One day, she discussed with me that as I was helping them,
she wanted to have a child with me which would be a point of contact between us
when I left the country.
I told her that if we did that, it could cause a problem for me
because I was a foreigner in the country.
She said I should know how to control the issue.
Finally, I started having an affair with her.
She then got pregnant and had a child for me.
My wife doesn't know anything of what I am saying now.
This is her first time of hearing all of these things.
So, this is the first time your wife is hearing this from you?
Yes, Man of God.
She suspected me but I was not in a position to say anything to her.
That woman used the child to threaten me.
Whenever she asked for something
or asked me to come to her house, which I didn't want to do,
she would say she would carry her child - my child, and drop it at my house.
The woman is a family friend
but I didn't want anything that would cause a problem between me and my wife.
My wife took her as a sister and always did her hair for her.
During our wedding, she was with us and helped us with everything we were doing.
My wife thought she was my sister.
Ok. Madam, how are you?
You should thank God; you should not be disturbed.
It is the time now God wants to fortify this marriage.
If there is no marriage between you and him, I would let you know.
I see this is a relationship from God; this is a marriage from God.
No matter the case, like Apostle Paul said, "What can separate me from the love of Christ".
Whatever happened, don't worry.
So, for you to know that he is not fit.
Do you know the woman he is talking about?
Yes.
I know the woman; she is like a sister, a family friend to me.
During our wedding, she organised her own committee of friends
and did her own committee of friends personally
because we were close together.
She is like a sister and family friend to us.
She has six children already.
The seventh one - I thought it was the woman's son.
I didn't know the seventh one is my husband's son.
I am here; I am confused and don't know what to do.
Please.
Are you hearing it for the first time now?
Yes, this is my first time to hear this.
Ok, it's alright.
I think the woman is around?
Yes, Man of God.
Because she is ... Madam, why are you panting?
It's alright.
So, I'm the one who said they should bring the woman.
She never knew you would be here; she never knew it would be like this.
Maybe, she probably thought I want to cement their marriage.
Ok, it's alright.
Madam, don't worry. After the service, I need to see the family.
But simple, viewers - what I want to see them for is simple.
Next Sunday, they will come out to give testimony.
This is your wife.
Okay?
I will...
Mr & Mrs Emmanuel - Prophecy Confirmation
Please forgive me.
Ok, it's alright.
So, I will meet the other woman, and I will talk to her.
But one thing is clear.
That child is this family's child.
You cannot reject him; he is your husband's child.
But she will leave your marriage and God will forgive your husband and forgive her.
The child belongs to this family. Okay?
But I want to assure you, this marriage is yours.
I will let you see the reason why you can't leave the marriage.
You will begin to enjoy the joy of this marriage from now on.
Okay? I will be meeting you people.
So, the woman should wait.
Thank you. The evangelists will meet the woman, entertain her
and give her a place to sit. She should not run away.
Madam, give me your hand.
Did you listen to me?
Ok, it's alright. I will see you.
Ok, go and wait for me.
Mr & Mrs Emmanuel - Prophecy Confirmation
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I know it doesn't mean anything to many of us here.
Some would just laugh over there and say, "Ah, see o!"
The day God will catch up with you, you will know it means a lot!
Some say, "Hehe! No problem".
The day God will catch up with you!
Ok. So, thank you.
I will personally see the woman and settle the matter.
The woman will go for deliverance today, prayer today, and she will quit the marriage.
We don't want them to just quit the marriage with disagreement and hatred.
To quit this kind of relationship, the whole thing will be to understand both sides,.
and this man can continue --
I know for many of you, you see it differently.
Sometimes, God can speak good through the bad.
That is God for you.
I know many of you, because of this, you quit the marriage.
A lot of marriages - there are many people here who quit their marriage
because of what happened - that kind of thing.
But today, have you got the right marriage now?
Whatever happens, examine it in the light of God.
Anything that happens in your marriage, ask God what He says about it.
In every situation, what does He say?
The answer is not to quit but the first thing is to ask God His mind -
what is His opinion, His suggestion concerning what happened -
before you think of either quitting or staying.
When something happens, no matter how big, what does He say.
In every situation, God has something to say.
So, we don't just quit anything -
either marriage, relationship, business partnership or whatever -
whatever relationship at all.
No matter what happened.
If God first brought this relationship, it is the same God that will release you and release him,
not crisis, not situation.
We should not because of situation release ourselves or quit the relationship.
No matter the situation, what does He have to say
because He is the Father of the relationship.
If not, you will leave this relationship and meet someone who has quit a relationship because of trouble.
The two of you will meet.
You quit the relationship because of trouble
and you meet someone who quit a relationship because of trouble.
Two of you - two troubles will meet.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If you quit this relationship because of trouble - either embarassment, betrayal or whatever -
and you quit, where will you get someone who has not quit a relationship before because of trouble?
If you quit this relationship without healing,
you will meet someone who quit a relationship without healing.
The two of you will meet.
The way you quit this relationship is the way you will meet the new relationship.
So much of the trouble we have today is because of the relationships we quit every day.
Business partner, marriage, friend - the way you quit them -
you just quit a relationship.
The person who is a criminal or is bad today, may be a messiah tomorrow, if you endure.
We have seen a person who you say betrayed you, disappointed you,
and you quit and leave him.
Now later, it is the same person you will meet in the future that stands to be your saviour.
You now say, "Ah!"
Life is just like that.
God owns our future. You don't know what the future holds.
The bad today can be the best tomorrow and the best today can be bad tomorrow.
The criminal today can be the saviour tomorrow.
A dishonest person can be trustworthy tomorrow.
I mean, life is just like that.
After the reconciliation with the family, Mr Emmanuel came back two weeks later
to testify of how God redeemed his marriage.
Let's listen to him.
TESTIMONY CONTINUES
My name is Mr Emmanuel.
I am from Togo.
The woman beside me is my wife.
I am married to a Nigerian; she is from Ebonyi State (Nigeria).
During the prophetic service on 10th December, the man of God prophesied that there is a man
here who secretly rented a house for another woman outside, who is me.
Today, we thank God.
After that, the man of God saw us, reconciled the family, counselled us and settled everything.
Now, I have received my child.
The child belongs to my wife and she will call my wife 'mother'.
I want to thank the man of God for him to allow himself to be used by God to settle this case.
Before I came here, I was like a man who was half dead.
I could not sleep. I did not have peace.
But since then, I can sleep; sometimes, my wife would be the one to wake me.
Before, I could wake up more than six times during the night.
Now, the love is different from before.
Now, we are living better than before, I know that this is the beginning of the wedding.
Thank you.
Amen. Let's clap for Jesus Christ!
That is a testimony after the prophecy and prayer by the man of God.
After meeting the family, he said his life is settled once again.
Before now, he was confused, restless; everthing was upside down.
There was no peace in his heart.
But now, there is peace.
The right knowledge of God has settled peace in the family.
So, let's hear from madam.
Mr Emmanuel & Wife - Reconciliation Testimony
My name is Mrs Chika.
I am a Nigerian, married to a Togolese.
The man beside me is my husband.
I am here to thank God for what He has done in our lives
through the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua, for restoring our marriage and family.
I am here to thank God.
We are happy; the man of God has settled and counselled us.
We are happy. We are here to thank God for that.
Amen.
Have you also forgiven your husband from your heart?
Yes, I have forgiven my husband, and I am ready to take the child as mine.
Amen. Let us clap for Jesus Christ!
I don't have anything to say more than thank you because I didn't know a day like this would come.
Now, I love my wife more than before.
To my greatest surprise, she accepted the child as her own.
I thank God for everything.
I thank God Almighty, in Jesus' name.
Thank You, Jesus. Let's clap for Jesus one more time!
So, Madam, regarding this issue, can you tell us - you met with the man of God,
and the man of God through the power of the Holy Spirit has intervened in this matter --
We met with the man of God.
The man of God prophesied to me that I'm going to have my own baby.
So, I'm happy. I'm ready to take the child as mine.
Amen. Glory be to God! So, you could hear that.
The man of God also released a prophetic word to her
that now, as she prepares to take this child as her own child,
that God will through that act bless her.
She is coming back to also testify about that.
We believe that it shall be according to as God has spoken, in Jesus' name.
So, right now, without further ado, we'd like to invite the lady -
the child's mother - into our midst.
True to her word, Mrs Chika lovingly accepts the little child as her own biological child.
Shall we put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Just as she was divinely advised by the man of God and also promised to comply,
the madam has taken the child from the biological mother
and has accepted to take the child as her own child.
This is my son from now, and I'm happy.
Let us clap for Jesus!
Thank you. God bless you.
Madam, we thank God Almighty for everything.
We believe, having been invited here over this issue,
and God has intervened in this matter, what do you have to say?
Emmanuel! (God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
My name is Mrs Charity.
I'm from Ebonyi State.
Okay.
I thank God for today.
I'm here to apologise to my sister
and hand over the child to the family
so that the wife will take care of the child.
I'm grateful.
I also thank the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua, for revealing it.
I really thank God.
I also ask her to forgive me and forget.
Ok, you have heard it all. Glory be to God in the highest!
Hallelujah! Let us clap for Jesus Christ!
So, madam, you have heard from the sister.
She is apologising for all that happened in the past.
We all know that all men make mistakes but mistakes are correctable.
By the grace of God, all the mistakes of the past have been corrected today,
and as she has spoken, what is your response, madam?
I have forgiven her .
Put your hands together for Jesus Christ!
I have forgiven you.
Thank you. God bless you.
Now that this marriage has been sustained,
and God Almighty has restored this marriage,
what could have broken the marriage
in the past
the Lord Almighty has taken care,
and today, the marriage has been cemented, even closer than ever before.
Madam, now that you have taken up this responsibility to take care of this child,
we also want to encourage you to do that faithfully,
knowing fully well that you are looking upon the face of God for your own blessing.
And as you take care of this child, as advised by the man of God himself,
this blessing will come speedily
and very soon you are coming back with your own child
to testify to the goodness of God, in Jesus' name.
So, as from today, you have said that you have now become the mother of the boy,
and we also thank you for listening to the words of the anointed man of God.